某一天，在世界盡頭的一個小鎮
One Day, in a town at the edge of the world.
潮水退去不再回歸
The tide went out and never returned.
大海毫無徵兆地消失
The sea just left without warning.
起初人們只是困惑
At first people were little more than puzzled.
他們開始了無休無止的爭論
They continued to gossip and fight over the same old things.
後來寂靜蔓延
But soon a silence began to permeate the township.
荒蕪的未知世界降臨在人們眼前
A desert of unbelievable magnitude was beginning to form before their very eyes.
家人和朋友今日在此相聚
We come together as family and friends
為他送別，為他祭奠
to farewell him and to grieve him.
尤其是你們，他的家人
we think especially of you, his family
Andrew, Penny, Jonathan.
你們失去了一位父親，一位公公，和一位祖父
For the loss of a father, a father-in-law and grandfather.
我們的哀思包含著對過去
Part of our grief may be regret for things done
或者未盡之事的悔意
or left undone.
說過的話
words said...
還有未曾說出口的那些
...or words never said.
在我父親的洞穴裡
你好
Yes?
Andrew在嗎？
Is Andrew there?
你一定是Paul
You must be Paul.
請進
Please, come in.
我是Penny
I'm Penny.
- 你好,Penny - 我是Andrew的妻子
- Hi,Penny. - Andrew's wife.
他們回來了
Ah, they're in here.
Andrew？
Andrew?
對不起
Sorry...
我的班機在香港延誤了
My plane was delayed in Hong Kong.
Paul？
Paul?
謝謝
Thanks.
- Andrew？ - 謝謝.
- Andrew? - Thanks.
Jonathan.
倫敦怎麼樣？你現在住在那裡吧？
So, how's London? Is that where you're based?
其實近期我住在伊斯坦布爾的時間更多
Actually I'm spending more time in Istanbul these days.
該死，我的平衡能力實在是...
Oh Jesus, fuck it, my balance is completely...fuck.
沒事的
It's fine, really.
你家不錯，看來你過得很好。
You have a nice place. You've done well.
我會讓Penny給你準備一間空房
I'll get Penny to make up a bed in a spare room.
- 不用了，我已經預訂了旅館 - 住下吧，不麻煩的
- No that's fine. I made reservations from London. - No,really,it's no trouble.
不用了，Andrew，謝謝你
No it's done. Andrew it's done.Thank you.
So...
他走了
He's gone.
是啊
Yeah.
Paul, 等等
Paul, wait!
Paul, 回來
Paul, come back!
Paul, 別走
Paul, don't leave!
Paul!
Andrew!
該死，忘了去見律師
Shit!The lawyers.
該死，對不起
Oh fuck!Sorry.
對不起，我打算去的
Sorry, I wanted to be there.
睡過頭了，情況怎麼樣？
Slept in.How did it go?
他留給你三分之一的財產
He left you a third.
那三分之二應該你拿
Well...you deserve two thirds.
我也只拿了三分之一
He left me a third as well.
剩下的呢？
And the rest?
他留給了慈善機構
He left it to a charity.
聽著，我趕時間
Listen, I need to move on this,
我要去清理果園和小屋，那我先告辭了, Paul
We need to clear the orchard and the cottage. I can't wait around, Paul.
我約了律師週二見你
I made an appointment for you to see the lawyer on Tuesday.
好，我一會兒順便就去
Well, I'll drop by and see him later.
你不能就這樣...
You can't just drop by and see
你不能就這樣順便去, Paul.
you can't just drop by and see them, Paul.
說得對
Right.
聽我說
Hey you know what?
我又接到了工作
Another job came through.So
明天要走了
I'm leaving, tomorrow.
你當然有更重要的事
Well you obviously have more important things.
我們就再過17年見吧
I'll see you in another 17 years.
Andrew, 別這樣
Come on Andrew, don't be such an old
別怎樣？
Come on Andew, don't what?
你才來了幾天, Paul？兩天？
How long have you been here, Paul? Two days?
你沒忘了當時你就是這樣一走了之的吧
Forget the fact that this all just leaves me and
媽死的時候
you're just like when mum died.
你他媽別提她, Andrew.
Oh leave mum the fuck out of it, Andrew.
對她尊重點
At least have the decency to do that.
尊重？
Decency?
你以為你比我強？
You think you're the one being decent?
帶著一口英國腔站在這裡趾高氣昂
Swanning in here like some bloody film star with your accent?
你什麼都不知道, Andrew.
You know nothing about me, Andrew.
聽著，拿著這個
Listen, he would have wanted you to have these.
差點忘了
I almost forgot.
會議上他們給我的
They handed me this at the council meeting.
葬禮那天你忘在了酒吧
You dropped it at the pub the afternoon of the service.
沒有它你可能回不了家了
It could be useful getting home.
你沒必要騙我, Paul
You didn't have to lie to me, Paul.
我們並沒有希望你會出現
We weren't expecting you in the first place.
為了記住過去——Jax
你灑的可是好酒
That's good wine you're spilling.
你怎麼發現這個地方的
How did you find this place?
我聽到音樂聲
I heard music.
媽媽不知道這裡？
Mom doesn't know about this place?
她不知道
No, she doesn't.
沒事
It's OK.
你留下吧
You can stay.
世界盡頭的某一天
One day in a town at the edge of the world.
潮水退去不再回歸
The tide went out and never returned.
你們什麼時候能知道結果
When do you think you'll learn?
把血樣拿回來之後，要過幾天
As soon as we get these blood samples back and the swabs, a couple of days.
我會多留幾天，幫忙清理屋子
I've extended my trip. I'll sort the house out.
Paul
謝謝
Thanks.
喝點綠茶
Green tea.
他在那兒幹什麼？
What's he doing down there?
他們在處理屋子的細菌，但願不會有什麼問題
There's been an outbreak of some virus. I'm praying they're okay.
他很關心你, Paul.
He cares about you, Paul.
他都沒有告訴Jonathan他還有個叔叔
He never told Jonathan about me.
我們都有處理問題的不同方式
We each have our own way of dealing with things.
你和我媽太像了
I can't believe how much you look like mum.
她是誰？
Who is she?
希望
That's hope.
她在哭？
Is she crying?
思考
She's thinking.
關於什麼？
About what?
很多
Many things.
Turin Brakes "Full Of Stars"
上帝
Jesus!
你在這裡幹什麼？
What are you doing here?
我找到了這個沒有人注意的地方，所以...
It's just a place that I found that no one else comes to, I just...
他讓你來的嗎？
Did he let you come here?
不是
No.
沒有人知道我來這裡
No one knows that I come here.
我得走了
I should probably go.
你是該走了
Yeah, I think you should.
給你幾分鐘，趕快收拾東西走人
I'll give you a couple of minutes to get your shit together and get out.
記者退出普利策獎提名
Paulie!
- Paulie Prior？ - 嗨, Winnie.
- Paulie Prior? - Hey, Winnie.
瞧瞧這是誰
Look who it is
你還好嗎？
How are you doing?
葬禮那天我在找你
I was looking for you at the service and I thought
我知道你會回來的，都認不出你了
I bet the little bugger is here somewhere. And I dont' even recognize him.
我遇到了一些情況
Ah no I had some complications.
那可不太好，你記得Pat吧
Oh that's a shame. Hey you remember Pat.
Pat, 瞧瞧這是誰，是Paulie
Pat, look, look who it is. It's Paulie
Seager老師!
Miss Seager!
Well, well...
嗨, Paul.
Hey, Paul.
我都不知道你還在這兒
I had no idea you were still here.
你以為我從地球上消失了？
What? you thought I'd dropped off the face of the earth?
聽聽他的一口英國腔
And he even has the fancy bloomin plummy accent.
戰爭
War zones.
從盧旺達的屠殺
From the genocide in Ruwanda
到中東的不斷戰爭
to the ceaseless fighting in the Middle East
還有波斯尼亞衝突帶來的恐慌
and the horrors of the Bosnian conflict.
戰爭地區對你們將要見到的這個人來說
War zones have been both home and work
在過去十年成為了家園和工作地
for the last decade to the man you are about to meet.
他的勇氣和敬業
A man whose dedication and courage
為他贏得了崇高的國際榮譽
has gained him an international reputation of the highest merit.
更不用說
Not to mention
它的報導和攝影作品獲獎無數
the numerous awards he has received for both his articles and photographs,
他曾經是我的學生
and that he is an old dear student of mine
和你們一樣在這裡上過課
who I taught in these very buildings.
由請Paul Prior
I present to you Paul Prior.
謝謝
Thank you.
剛才的介紹實在不敢當, Seagar老師
That was a very generous introduction, Miss Seagar.
我學生時的成績可不怎麼樣
Yeah, my school reports were never that good.
事實上
The truth is that
有很多人對我惡言相向
I've been called many things,
離開這裡之後遭受過太多非議甚至辱罵
many worse things since I last stepped foot in this building
貪得無厭，寄生蟲，吸血鬼
vulture, parasite ,leech
不過我發現不同語言的侮辱，聽來是相似的
And it's amazing how insults in most languages sound pretty much the same.
我曾經
I was once
被囚禁三天，並當眾侮辱
held captive for three days and publicly urinated on.
我不知道該說什麼
I don't really know what to say,
但是很高興回答你們的問題
but I'd be happy to answer any questions that you might have.
他曾經獲得普利策獎的提名
He was a finalist for the Pulitzer
普利策？什麼鬼東西？
Pulitzer? What the hell is that?
是一個大獎
It's a huge prize.
他當時有三分之一的機會勝出
He had a one in three chance of winning it as well.
他在戰地攝影，寫戰爭報道
這些他都在行
你怎麼知道這些東西的
How do you know this shit?
我讀過一篇訪問
I read an interview.
聽著像個獨行俠
Sounds like a lone wolf.
對了，我想刺個紋身
That reminds me, I'm thinking of getting a tattoo.
在這裡紋個獨角獸
A little unicorn, right here.
為什麼？
Why?
Steve也有一個？
Steve has exactly the same one?
我只是覺得會很酷
No I just think it would be cool.
那麼
So anyway.
你和Jake怎麼樣了？
How'd it go with Jake?
走開！
Piss off.
告訴我
Tell me!
Well...
我們在灑滿月光的海邊漫步
first of all we had a moonlight stroll down the beach
享用了燭光晚餐
and a candle light dinner
然後他說我的眼睛很漂亮
and then he told me what beautiful eyes I had.
真的？
Really?
當然不是
No, you dyke.
他只知道喝酒
He only got drinks to go on the Big Day Out.
你知道他那樣子
You know he was like
"嘿，老兄！嘿，小妞！」
Yo man. Yo bitch.
他就是這樣
And I think it should be quite so obvious.
我剛看了這裡的報紙
I was reading the local rag today.
還是頭版
Front page.
天哪
Oh God.
我已經忘了這是個小地方了
I'd forgotten how quiet is, really.
來了這裡，我一直有該死的耳鳴
I've had this bloody ringing in my ears ever since I got here.
也許你應該改變一下
Maybe the change here will do you good.
如果你對做戰地記者已經感到厭倦
Like I said, if you ever get bored photographing war.
你不是說真的吧？
You weren't being serious, were you?
我手下有三個教員辭職了, Paul.
I'm three staff down, Paul.
我知道這你不太能接受，但...
I know it might sound desperate, but
Pat, 我不知道該怎麼做，我可從沒教過書
Pat, I'd be hopeless, I've never taught in my life. Come on.
你可以用你的方式，那沒問題吧？
You went out and made something of yourself. What can beat that?
這裡一半的孩子都不瞭解外面的世界
Half these kids don't even know what's on the other side of those hills.
Paul!
Paul給Jonathan的
Paul gave Jonathan this.
這相機變焦很好
It's got a good zoom lens.
這太貴重了
It's much, much too kind.
沒事的
No, it's fine.
我現在都用數碼的
Honestly, I'm using digital these days.
如果想成為好的攝影師，就要有好的相機
If you're going to be a serious photographer, you need a good zoom lens.
明天見
See you tomorrow then.
晚安，Paul
Goodnight. Paul.
晚安
Goodnight.
Jonathan說他在學校作了演講
Jonathan said he gave a talk at the school.
孩子們都喜歡他
Apparently the kids really liked him.
這很好
Good.
我可以做你了嗎？
Can I fuck you now?
天哪，你用詞太不注意了
God! You've got a way with words!
對不起，那你想做什麼？
Sorry, what do you want to do then?
你在幹嘛
What you all doing man?
玩玩
Just playing.
小心點
Just play carefully.
該死！去你的！
Shit! Fuck you!
你不該動的
You were meant to stay still.
你氣色不錯
You look well.
不如過去了
Well, used more like it.
你變了
It's different.
一口英國腔
You have an accent. So English.
你這麼覺得？
You think?
這也是難免的
Well, it was inevitable.
厭倦了被人叫做澳大利亞人
Sick of being called an Australian.
好吧
Fair enough.
來一根吧
Help yourself.
我戒了
Oh no, I quit.
有孩子嗎？
Kids?
兩個
Two.
一男一女
One of each.
記得Ben嗎？
Remember Ben?
Ben Steimer
Ben Steimer.
對
Yeah.
你走後一年半我們在一起了
We got together about 18 months after you left.
女兒五歲的時候他死了
He died when Elvis was five.
摩托車禍
Motobike.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
那時我懷著Sam
I was pregnant with Sam at the time.
為了孩子，我決定開始工作
So I had the kids to think about and decided to keep the business running.
你做什麼？
What was that?
肉店
Butchery.
我是新西蘭個子最小的屠夫
Shortest butcher in New Zealand.
真的？
Really?
我是持剔骨刀的武士
Yeah well, I'm a ninja with a boning knife .
我不感到驚訝
No surprises there.
我經常看見你弟弟
I see your brother from time to time.
對，他一直很忙
Yeah, he's up to his neck in ostriches.
他沒離婚吧？我沒見過他妻子
Is he still married? I never see his wife.
沒有，她只是不常出門
No, yeah, I don't think she goes out much
我警告過你多少次了
How many times have I told you about leaving the gate to the pen open?
如果你以為我會還給你，那就錯了
If you think you're going to see this again you're mistaken.
你讓我噁心
You disgust me.
你要去見誰
Who the hell is this guy?
一個老朋友，沒什麼
Just an old school friend. It's no big deal.
沒什麼？
No big deal?
我的外套呢？
Where's my jacket?
Celia, 別忘了垃圾
Celia, It's rubbish night.
把袋子繫上，別讓狗跑進去，再見
And please tie the bags. I don't want dogs getting into them. Bye, bye.
我們等著你
Hey, we'll be waiting.
要幫忙嗎？
Need a hand with that?
作業完成了？
Done your homework?
請把腳拿開
Will you please take your foot away?
我可是關心你
What? Just to see if you've done your homework.
問問而已
Just asking.
我們以前也這樣做過
I'm sure we used to be able to do this.
你會想到我嗎？
Did you think of me?
我怕見到你
I was terrified of seeing you.
記得你以前寫的那些詩和故事嗎？
You remember those poems and stories you used to write?
那時我想寫成歌，我們會出一張唱片
I was going to put music to them, release an album.
我們的樂隊叫什麼名字來著？
What were we were going to call ourselves?
是"silly bastards"嗎？
What was it? Was it "silly bastards"?
"Stupid Buggers"
"Sick Motherfuckers", "Sick Fuckers", 是嗎？
"Sick Motherfuckers", "Sick Fuckers", wasn't it?
是"Sick Puppy"
"Sick Puppy", actually.
還有演唱會
Live at the Hammersmith.
沒有如願以償，回過頭來看看曾經的自己
Yeah, see that's me. Eight years behind what was going on. But, you know,
現在還是會白日做夢
still thinking I had created it all for myself.
Celia
嗨
Hi.
我在採訪本地的名人
I've got an assignment where I have to interview an important local community member.
我在你和造灌溉渠的Aiken先生之間選擇了你
And it was a choice between you and Mr Aiken who set up the irrigation main.
你願意接受採訪嗎？
I was just wondering if I could interview you?
我可以進屋嗎？
Can I come in?
有真咖啡嗎？
Is there real coffee?
當然，要喝哪種
Sure. How do you have it?
Macchito, 謝謝
Macchito, thanks.
我叫Celia
I'm Celia by the way.
你有問題要問吧？
I gather you do have some questions.
嗯，對
Ah Yes. Ah Yeah.
你怎樣走上現在這條路的
So, how did you get to do what you do?
我在倫敦一家報社工作
I was working for a paper in London on local articles,
他們需要人手去波斯尼亞
and they needed somebody to go to Bosnia.
我知道，你在惠靈頓做過排字工人
That right, yeah. You were working as a typesetter in Wellington,
去倫敦學新聞
and you studied journalism in London,
後來成為專欄作家
and found your break as a feature article writer,
又稱為路透社的戰地記者
and then a field journalist for Reuters.
過去的三年半你在往返於
And for the past three and a half years you've been solidly freelance living
倫敦、伊斯坦布爾、巴黎
between London, Istanbul and Paris.
說得不錯
Well done. Yes. That's it.
看來你下了點功夫
You've really done your homework.
人們一定為你做這樣的工作感到擔心
People must worry about you a lot doing this kind of work.
你的妻子？孩子？
Your wife? Children?
我未婚
No, not married.
單身？是
Single? Yes.
目睹戰爭的感受是怎樣的
What's it like going to war? Just to watch?
我不是去目睹，而是去記錄
I'm not there to watch. I'm there to record.
你的傷疤是因為戰爭留下的？
Is that how you got those scars?
12歲時騎車摔的
I fell off my bike when I was 12 coming down a gravel track.
沒有別的傷疤？
No other scars?
你還喝不喝你的macchito？
Are you going to drink your macchito?
你經歷過最困難的情況是？
What's the hardest thing you have to deal with?
上帝，你的問題真難回答
Jesus. Are these going to get any easier?
不知道，在那兒找廁所倒是相當困難
I don't know, finding a loo when you need one,which always seems to be pretty fucking impossible.
為什麼你不在聖誕節那天過生日？
Why don't you celebrate your birthday on Christmas?
這你又是在哪裡看到的
Now tell me, which article did you read that one in?
你拍那女孩照片的那天是你的生日
It was your birthday when you took that photo of that girl.
那張作品獲得了普利策獎
The one you won the Pulitzer for.
提名
I was shortlisted.
我聽說你被提名後
I read that when you got nominated
自動退出
you withdrew the entry.
說來話長
Long story.
我的錄音帶有120分鐘
I've got a 120 minute tape.
我當時在Grozny
I was in Grozny
聽說俄國佬將要遭到一次攻擊
I heard about an offensive that was being mounted against the Russians.
朋友們警告我不要寫這篇報道
I was warned by some friends not to write about it
以防俄國人得知並發起反擊
in case the Russians caught whiff about what was going to happen.
你怎麼做的
So what did you do?
我還是寫了
Wrote the article.
發給路透社
Then I declined sending it through to Reuters.
他們還是發現了
They found out anyway.
為了報復，在城外的一個村莊殘殺了100多個平民
And they retaliated by massacring over 100 civilians in the village outside the city.
那晚我喝了一夜酒 其中幾個朋友幾小時後也被殺害了
.And I'd been out all night drinking with people who were killed a few hours later.
照片中的女孩
The girl in the photo was the
是唯一的倖存者
was the only survivor.
你認識她嗎？
Did you know her?
不
No.
當時有別人在場嗎？
Was there anyone else around?
沒有別人
Not at the time, no.
只有你？
Just you?
只有我
Just me.
後來呢？
So then what?
我想你快沒電了
I think your batteries are running flat.
你是
Are you...
你是Ben Steimer的女兒？
Are you Ben Steimer's daughter?
你知道他
Did you know him?
我們是同學
Yeah, we went to school together.
一張孩子的照片
It's a photo of a baby.
誰的
Whose?
不知道，我需要嗎？
I don't know. Do I need to?
看看那條手鏈
Yeah, look at the bracelet.
看著 "Celia, 27/2/87".
No, look! "Celia, 27/2/87".
那是我走後的八個月
That's roughly 8 months after I left.
我16年前就寄出這張照片了
I sent that photo nearly 16 years ago.
為什麼？
Why did you send it?
為什麼寄, Jax？
Why did you send it, Jax?
你想聽我的解釋？
You want an explanation?
你知道你徹底消失了嗎, Paul？
Do you know what's it like to be invisible, Paul?
一張明信片
Even just a postcard.
一個電話都沒有
A phone call.
Sid, 把它放那兒
Hi Sid, up there next to the porkers.
Patti Smith "Free Money"
都過去了，好嗎？
It's in the past. OK?
別管它
Just leave it.
你需要復件嗎？
Will you be needing a copy of that?
不，謝謝
No, thank you.
重新發行
上帝，我想我該從那群電視鬼中解脫一下
Oh my god. I think I need rescuing from these TV blokes.
是本好書吧？
Is it a good book, is it?
"未知之雲", 好神秘
"The Cloud of Unknowing", Sounds mysterious.
你從哪兒來
Where are you from?
我從哪兒來
Where am I from?
很遠的地方
A long way from here.
我也是，不介意我坐這兒吧？
Me too. Mind if I join you?
喝一杯？
Want a drink?
好
I'd love one.
吻我
Kiss me.
是這本嗎？
Am I warm?
近了
Getting closer.
這本？
Warmer?
差不多了
Getting warmer.
這本？
Warmer?
就快了
Warmer, in springtime.
這本!
Here!
我們孤獨地來到這個世界
Alone we are born
孤獨地死去
And die alone
看那雪山之上的紅色微光
Yet see the red-gold cirrus Over snow mountain shine
在山路上前行
Upon the upland road
陌生的你請放慢腳步
Ride easy, stranger
仰拜天空吧，憤怒的心
Surrender to the sky, your heart of anger
不要畏懼無限的可能性，兒子
Don't be frightened of possibilities, son.
她是偉大的象徵
She's a wonderful mistress.
沒事的
It's ok.
睡吧
Go back to sleep.
我只是在這裡幫一陣子忙
I'm helping out for a couple of weeks.
我沒做過老師，請大家見諒
And I'm new at this, so be patient with me.
誰知道英語中有多少詞語
Who knows how many words there are in the English language?
一萬
10 thousand.
字典上有超過75萬
Dictionary. There's actually over 750,000 words.
我想讓你們每個人選一個詞語
And I was a -- I thought maybe you could all choose a word.
無論哪個詞，最好是對你們來說有一定意義的
Any word, doesn't matter what. Preferably something that means something to you.
關於這個詞寫一些東西
And compose something on this word.
無論什麼都可以，可以是關於你們自己
Anything. It could be just a static image of you if you think that's easier.
這樣我可以認識你們
Just so I get an idea of who you all are.
也看看現在自己處於什麼情況
And what the F--- I've gotten myself into.
希望
Hope.
她的思想是一座墳墓，她的心靈是一座島嶼
Her mind is a graveyard. Her heart is an island.
我們並非深交，但卻相識一生
She and I are not good friends but I've known her all my life.
她離我如此近，卻又那麼遠
She sits in my belly hollow and distant.
她的耳語從未撫慰我的心靈
And her whispered words of encouragement will never comfort me.
媽媽？
Mom?
我中了她的毒，她虛偽的承諾
I'm on to her tricks. Her false promises.
"走開", 我說，"我今天很忙"" 有事要做"
"Go away", I tell her. "I'm busy today."" I've got things to do."
她永遠不會離開
This acquaintance never knows when to leave.
問題不是她為何成為了我的朋友
It's not a question of why she befriended me in the first place.
而是我為何沒有拒絕
It's more a question of why I choose to let her stay.
茶袋!茶袋!
Tea bag! Tea bag!
茶袋!
Tea bag!
- 茶袋! - 放開她，你們這群畜牲!
- Tea bag! - Leave her alone, you fucking animal!
茶袋!茶袋!
Tea bag! Tea bag!
你的膝蓋破了
Your knee's bleeding.
我知道，我摔了一跤
I know. I fell.
我來幫你看看
Come on. Let's take a look at it, then.
幾周的時間過去
Weeks passed
依然沒有大海的痕跡
and there was still no sign of the ocean.
人們更加擔心
The people grew worried.
他們決定派人去尋找
It was decided to send a small group to search for it
滿心希望把它找回來
in the hope of bringing it back.
大家請注意
All right attention please.
請聽好
I would appreciate it if everyone listened.
包括你在內，Brook
That includes you, Mr Brook.
昨天以後你們見過Celia嗎？
Look. Have any of you seen Celia since yesterday?
沒有？如果你們見到她
No? Well, if she gets in touch with any of you,
告訴我好嗎？
you know where to find me, okay?
謝謝
Thanks.
大家安靜，都不是沒見過警察
All right. Settle down. We've all seen a police officer before.
Paul，能和你聊兩句嗎？
Paul? Look, Just wondering. Can I have a word for a second?
我上課要遲到了
I'm already late for a class.
不會太長的
It won't take long.
回去上課
Back to class.
Paul？
Paul?
Pat, 沒事的，我只是在幫點忙
Hey, Pat, It's fine. I'm just helping out with something.
謝謝, Pat.
Thanks, Pat.
週末你見過Celia嗎？
Hey, did you see Celia on the weekend?
沒有
No.
她來過你家吧？
She used to visit though, right.
對
Yeah.
她會來借書
She came by sometimes to borrow books.
她多久來一次
How often did she pop by?
大多是週日吧
She liked to drop by most Sundays I guess, yeah.
- Liked？ - Likes.
Liked? Likes.
我用的是現在時
I said likes, I think.
我想我知道Celia喜歡什麼
Ah see cause I think I know what Celia likes.
她小的時候我就認識她了，她是我女兒最好的朋友
I mean I've known her since she was a little kid. She's my daughter's best friend.
我也知道你發郵件給她，讓她週末去找你
I also know that you sent her an e-mail on the weekend asking her to come by and visit.
我瞭解到，那時她不太高興
She wasn't too happy about that from what I understand.
我知道這事兒, Paul
You see I know this, Paul
因為Miso答應她把她送到你家
because Miso agreed to drop her off.
她是去過我那兒
Actually she did drop by briefly.
你那果園不錯
It's nice out there at the orchard.
安靜，無人打擾
Quiet. Private.
你為什麼留下來？
So why did you stay on?
幫一個朋友的忙
Favour for a friend.
你們戀愛了多久？
How long did you guys go out for?
什麼？
What?
你和媽媽
om
她提到我了
Oh, she mentioned me.
你們什麼時候分手的？
When did you break up?
十七歲
God, seventeen.
Keep your leg still.
不要動
那天你寫的東西，我覺得
Listen, what you wrote the other day, I thought it was
考慮周到
well considered.
- 考慮周到 - 引人入勝
Well considered. Intriguing.
我喜歡你佈置的書房
I like what you've done here.
這些書是哪兒來的
Where did all these books come from?
他從沒告訴我
He never told me.
我想是保持神秘吧
Wanted to keep it a mystery, I suppose.
父親總是那樣的，不是嗎？
Father's have got a lot to answer for, huh?
嘿，美人
Hey beautiful.
對不起遲到了
Sorry I'm late.
她不會走遠的
She can't have gone far.
我和幾個朋友一會兒要去Lawrence那兒
Me and some mates are going to take a look around Lawrence later.
你能端那兩個嗎？
Can you bring those?
當然
Sure.
我要你寫的是有關移民的文章, Jake
I asked for an essay about the pros and cons of immigration, Jake
不是衝浪的好去處
not the best places to surf.
Louise, Tonga的元首是國王，不是總統
Louise, Tonga has a king, not a president.
我想香港除了舞廳外還有更多值得關注的地方, Miso.
I think you'll find there's more to life in Hong Kong than dance clubs, Miso.
比如說？秘密書會？
What? Like secret book clubs?
Paul!
O'Neil警官又來了
Sergeant O'Neil's back.
他還在上次的房間等你
He's waiting for you in the common room.
我告訴他你很忙
I told him you were busy.
你小時候寫的字不錯
You had nice handwriting as a kid.
這是她借的書嗎？
Is this one of the books she borrowed?
我沒有
I didn't
我沒有留下記錄
I didn't keep a record, to tell you the truth. I didn't.
什麼？你想著別的事吧
What? Other things on your mind, did you?
我們在路邊發現的，我想是你的東西
We found this on the side of the road, bet it came from your place.
我只是想知道它是怎麼到那兒的
Just want to know how it got there, that's all.
她跟你提起過要出走嗎？
Did she ever talk to you about leaving?
這裡的年輕人都想離開
Name a teenager around here who doesn't.
那可不一定
I know a few actually.
Stop.
睜開眼睛
OK. You can open your eyes.
生日快樂
Happy Birthday.
這是誰的歌
Who is this anyway?
Kiri Te Kanawa，你選的
Kiri Te Kanawa. You chose it.
她是誰
Who's she?
你不知道？
你連她都不知道，很該死
There are people in this country who would shoot you for asking that question.
你聽她的歌，才該死
There are people in this country who would shoot you for listening to it.
她在唱什麼？
So what's she singing about?
愛情
Love.
週六晚上你一般幹些什麼？
What do you normally do on a Saturday night?
不和我野餐的話，你會和誰一起
Who do you hang out with when you're not having picnics with me?
你會做什麼，參加聚會還是？
What do you do, go to parties or what?
如果你稱其為聚會的話
If you can call them that.
問這個幹嘛？你想加入？你可能會看到他們玩茶袋
Why? Do you wanna come along? You actually might get to see them tea bagging.
茶袋？那是什麼？
Tea bagging? What's that?
那個，是一群男孩把女孩灌醉
Well, That's when guys get a girl completely comatose
他們把那個伸進她的眼窩，然後拍下來
and then they take turns in lowering their testicles into her eye sockets and film it.
如果他們覺得有意思 會把照片寄給一個瘋狂的朋友
And if they're really kind they send a copy to a paranoid friend.
射了的最好，我不覺得那很有趣
First class is seminal? It's not funny.
我不知道我們在說什麼
I don't know what we're talking about.
上帝
Oh god.
我希望你離那些男孩遠些
Well I hope you keep your distance from those kind of guys is what I'm saying.
說說你和我媽吧，回到黑暗時代
So, tell me about you and mum, back in the dark ages.
沒有你說的那麼誇張
It wasn't that long ago.
Patti Smith "Horses"
我媽那時想這樣唱歌？
My mom wanted to sing like this?
你媽想成為Patti Smith
Your mother wanted to be Patti Smith.
跟我來，快
Come with me. Come on.
給你個驚喜
I'll show you something.
這是什麼地方？
Where did this place come from?
只有我和我爸知道
No one knows about it except me and my dad.
你們在這裡幹什麼？
So what are you doing here?
寫作
Write.
思考
Think.
神秘男孩
Mystery boy.
如此神秘
So many secrets.
你在幹嘛
What are you doing?
給你找些素材，呆子
Giving you something to write about, moron.
搖滾媽媽
Mom the rock star.
不敢相信她也有過夢想
It's hard to believe she even had a dream.
你想知道我的夢想是什麼嗎？
Do you want to know what my dream is?
想啊
Yeah.
我坐在西班牙的一間咖啡館
I'm sitting in a cafe in Spain.
不認識一個人，不懂一句話
And don't know a single person there. And I can't understand a single word that anyone's saying.
我握著一杯酒
I've got a glass of wine
看見海
and I can see the sea.
算了，還是不說了
Don't worry.
繼續啊，然後？
No, go on. And?
我只是寫作
I'm just writing.
然後
And yeah.
我不介意有沒有人看我的作品
And you know it doesn't matter if no one ever reads what I'm writing
我不想成名
I don't want to be famous.
我只是，只是想在那兒
I just, I just want to be there.
寧可寂寂無名，也不願迷失所在
Anyway, I'd rather be a no one somewhere than someone nowhere.
我已經整理好了行李
I've already packed my suitcase.
我沒有開玩笑
I'm not joking.
我沒有嘲笑你
I'm not laughing at you.
我也有過這樣的夢
I had a similar dream once.
真的嗎？
Really?
告訴我
Tell me.
有時我能看見...人們的臉
Sometimes I'd see...faces.
入睡之前，陌生的人
At night before I fell asleep, people I never met.
我不知道他們是誰
And I'd wonder who they were.
他們身在何處，他們所事何物
Where they might live, what they did.
奇怪的是
and it was strange
好像他們知道我在想著他們
because it was like they knew I was thinking about them.
你為什麼要做戰地記者？
Why did you become a war journalist?
你往往無法成為嚮往的自己
Who you set out to be is not always who you become.
事情發生了，計劃改變了
You know, Things happen. Plans change.
我也會看見他們
I see them too.
人臉
Faces.
我想給你個東西
I wanted to give you something.
Yeah, right.
我想你應該參加
I just, I think you should enter.
寫作比賽
你從來沒有說起過你的母親
You never talk about your mum.
我的母親？她是虔誠的教徒
My mum? She's very religious.
她告訴我上帝在安靜的角落藏了美好
She had these little sermons about the beauty God hides away in quiet corners.
你爸爸在這裡就是為了躲避這些吧
Is that what your dad was hiding from in here?
不，他們
No, they
她只是很安靜
I think she was just quiet, you know.
我父母很不同
My dad and her were very different.
我爸不相信任何事，他是無神論者
My dad didn't believe in anything. He's an atheist.
我弟弟和她很親近
My brother and her were very close.
我聽說她發生了意外
I heard she had an accident .
是的
Yeah she did.
她被診斷得了抑鬱癥
She was diagnosed as bi-polar, manic depression.
她沒有服醫生給的藥
Doctors prescribed lithium but she stopped taking it, I think.
發生了什麼？
What happened?
她站在河裡
She was standing in the river
在農場的後邊，她的手指向了空中的鷹
at the back of the property and she pointed up to this hawk in the sky.
我再次望向她時。她已經不在了
And then when I looked back she was gone.
兩天後找到了屍體
Found the body two days later, I think
這是你疏遠人事的原因嗎？
Is that why you push people away?
我想做什麼就做什麼，Celia. 我討厭打碎你的幻想
I do as I fucking please Celia. You know I hate to spoil your illusions.
但是外面的世界不是等待採摘的玫瑰
But the world out there isn't a bed of roses waiting to be picked
或者像你說的，一個酒吧裡的一杯好酒
or whatever it was you said, a glass of chardonnay in a fucking tapas bar.
你懂嗎？
You understand?
我沒有想過要冒犯你
It wasn't an insult.
對不起
Sorry.
沒事
OK.
嘿, Jax.
Hey, Jax.
嗨
Hi
我看到你這兒有煙，其實不想打擾你
I saw the smoke and I didn't want to disturb you
但是今天是你的生日，所以
but I remembered it was your birthday and so I
到車裡去
Get in the car
不
No.
Celia, 我受夠了
Celia, I'm sick of this.
我說到車裡去，到車裡去
I said get in the car. I said get in the car
你沒有權利來這裡趕我走，晚安，Paul
You have no right to be here. Night, Paul.
你把她帶來這裡，還給她酒？
You have the audacity to bring here and give her alcohol?
Jax, 不是你想的那樣
Jax, it's not what you think.
你以為你連我怎麼想的都知道？
You even presume to know what I think?
該死
Shit!
對不起
Excuse me.
我要找一本筆記，應該在這裡
I need a notebook. I know it's here somewhere.
對不起，爸爸
Sorry, dad.
不用道歉
There's nothing to be sorry for
只要你們注意著點就好
as long as you're being cautious.
當然
Yeah of course.
那我走了
I'll be on my way.
你不該來這兒的
You shouldn't be here.
他不在乎的
He doesn't care.
你也看到了
I mean you saw for yourself.
我在乎
I care.
你什麼意思？
What are you telling me?
你是說我不如你的想法重要？
That I'm not as important as what goes on in your head?
我的一部分是你無法擁有的
There's just parts of me you can't have.
沒有人可以
No one can.
嘿，你好嗎？
Hey. You ok?
現在別給我這個
I'd rather look at it at your place.
這是什麼？
What's this?
上帝
Jesus Christ.
她打的嗎？
Did she do this?
Celia，告訴我，誰打的
Celia tell me, who did it?
我不想說，不是我媽
I don't want to talk about it. It wasn't mom.
嘿，他在哪兒
Hey where is he?
Paul, 你幹嘛
Paul, what are you doing?
Paul, 你在我家幹嘛
Paul, what are you doing in my house?
他在哪兒, Jackie？
Where is he, Jackie?
怎麼了
What's going on?
就是這個混蛋嗎？
Is this the asshole?
什麼？這他媽是誰？
What? Who the fuck is this?
他媽閉嘴, Gareth!
Shut the fuck up, Gareth!
Paul, 出去
Paul, would you leave?
這就是傳說中的Paul啊
So this is the famous Paul.
你喜歡打小女孩是吧，你知道這是虐待？
You like beating up little girls, do you. You know it's assault, is what it is.
你再敢碰她，我殺了你
You touch her again. I'll kill you.
殺了我，啊？
Is that right, mate?
給我看清楚了，白癡
What do you call this, dickhead?
我只管好我自己的事
I always mind my own fucking business.
滾出我家，蠢人
Get out of my house, you fucking pricks.
管好你自己的事
Mind your fucking business.
你給我滾，清楚了嗎？
You cunt, you fuck off! Is that clear?
還想殺我嗎，蠢人
Still wanna fucking kill me, cunt?
Gareth, 你他媽進去
Gareth, Get the fuck inside.
進去！
Get the fuck inside!
你以為你可以闖進我家 在我孩子面前做出這樣的事？
You think you can come here and do this shit in front of my kids?
你看到她的傷嗎？你以為我還能做什麼？
Have you seen her fucking bruises? What did you think I was going to do?
她要忍受的還有更多，我要你離她遠點
She got a lot more than she got. I want you to stay away from her.
你改了出生證明
You changed the birth certificate.
你準備什麼時候告訴她？
When were you going to tell her about that?
不要再來煩我們，行嗎？
Just stay out of our lives, all right?
好啊
Yeah.
回頭見，Paul，該死的蠢人
See you around Paul, you fucking prick.
喂？
Hello?
Celia？
Celia?
她可能去了西班牙
She might have gone to Spain.
不不不，等等
No, no, no, wait.
我女兒秘密計劃去西班牙，他為她保密
My daughter plans on running off to Spain and he sees nothing.
我不認為那很正常
I don't call that irrelevant.
Jackie, 這也不是她第一次這樣做了
Come on Jackie, it's not like it's the first time she's done something like this.
太好了
Oh great.
好啊，你幫著他說話了？
How good, this is good. So you are defending him now?
那好，她具體是什麼時候說要去西班牙的？
Okay, so when exactly did she say she was running off to Spain?
她沒有，沒有說出來，我知道她有機票
She didn't. She didn't say. All I knew is she had the ticket.
我以為她會等學校放假再走，就是這樣
I thought she was going to leave when school was finished. That's all.
我不知道該怎麼想
I didn't know what to think.
我知道我是怎麼想的，我想你瘋了
Yeah well I know what I think. I think you are out of your mind.
她讓我保證不告訴任何人
She made me promise not to tell a soul.
我是她的媽媽
I'm her mother.
OK？
OK?
那她是什麼時候這樣做的呢？
When exactly did she make this promise Paul?
是你給她灌酒喝的時候嗎？
Was it when you were plying her with alcohol?
我沒有灌她，我只是給了她一杯，孩子能喝的
I wasn't plying her with alcohol. I gave her a glass, Jackie. A child could have drunk it.
孩子是喝了
A child did drink it.
是啊，那他打她的時候她也是那樣想的嗎？
Oh yeah. And did he think of that when he was punching the shit out of her?
還有別的
And the rest.
滾開，別把我扯進去
Fuck off. Don't bring me into it.
偷看她
Sneaking up on her.
趁她洗澡時故意去廁所
Pissing in the toilet while she was lying in the bath.
她跑得遠遠的就是為了躲著你，你他媽的...
If it took her going half way around the world to get away from you, you fucking a--.
你們留下
You two stay in here.
你去我辦公室，我和你單獨談
You, get in my office. I want a word alone.
他在說什麼？
What's he talking about?
他他媽說的是什麼？
What the fuck is he talking about
沒什麼!
Nothing!
告訴我你最後一次見她的情況，不要隱瞞
Tell me about the last time you saw her. Everything.
我把她送到門口，她拿著地圖
We were at the gate. She was carrying the atlas.
她告了別，然後離開
She said goodbye and she left.
沒有特殊的告別？
No special goodbyes?
沒有特殊的告別
No special goodbyes.
她有幾本書沒來得及讀
No, she had a couple of books she hadn't got around to read
我告訴她可以留著
and I told her she could keep them.
這些書的名字？
Names of these books?
這有關嗎，我不知道
Oh fuck say, what does it matter? I don't know.
Janet Frame的"Owls Do Cry", 還有一本
"Owls Do Cry", by Janet Frame, and another one,
Camus的"The Outsider", 應該是這本
Camus, "The Outsider", I think it was.
是Camus，不是canoe. C-a-m-u-s
That's Camus not canoe. C-a-m-u-s.
自以為是的傢伙
You smug prick.
不是每個人都想去歐洲的
Not all of us had to run off to Europe, mate.
旅行日記
Travel Diary
護照
passport
"失蹤的女孩和老師共處一密室"
"Missing girl, teacher, shared secret den"
我想你已經看過了
I guess you've seen this.
小鎮的閒言碎語
Small town bloody gossip.
我不知道怎樣處理, Paul.
I don't know what to do about this, Paul.
學校高層開了會
The board of trustees have called a meeting.
我知道你是無辜的
You don't deserve this.
沒事的, Pat.
You know it's fine, Pat.
我也該走了，說真的
It's time I left anyway. Honestly.
嘿，Jonathan.
Hey! Jonathan.
Jonathan？
Jonathan?
Jonathan!
上車
Get in!
Jonathan, 上車，外面太冷了
Jonathan, get in the car, it's bloody freezing.
快
Come on.
繫上安全帶
Put your seat belt on.
你和她發生關繫了嗎？
Were you having sex with her?
什麼？
What?
你知道我說的是誰
You know who.
誰說的
Who said that?
學校裡的孩子，說你在床上給她特殊訓練
Kids at school, said you were giving her special coaching in bed.
你相信他們？
And you believed them?
你相信了
Huh, and you believed
照相機呢？最近沒有看見你用它
How's that camera going? I haven't seen you with it lately.
日復一日，越來越多的人開始尋找
As the days went on, more and more people went looking.
人們四處尋找
The people searched far and wide
但是大海消失得毫無蹤影
but the ocean had vanished without a trace.
曾經富饒的大地
The quiet land once bountiful
變得堅硬和貧瘠
had become hard and unyielding.
地平線上的某物現了形
Then a shape appeared on the horizon.
透過恨意的強光，人們看到
Through a blaze of hate the people saw
翻滾的海水向他們襲去
what looked like tumbling water rolling towards them.
激烈之浪灌過小鎮
A wave of excitement passed through the town
當他們焦急地盼著大海回歸
as they anxiously watched the ocean return.
當它逼近的時候，一切突變
But as it grew closer the shape began to alter and mutate.
翻滾的海水其實是大群野馬
What looked like tumbling water was in fact wild horses.
人們眼看馬群四處逼近
Everywhere they turned they saw horses drawing closer and closer.
他們的興奮轉為了恐懼
Their excitement turned to fear.
他們的恐懼成為了恐慌
And their fear became panic,
眼見馬群的前進無可阻擋
for it seemed that nothing could stop their advance.
就如大海的消失
Which as the ocean's disappearance
來得毫無徵兆
had come without warning.
但是沒有人
But then no one,
甚至沒有一刻時間
not even for a moment,
能夠質疑為何，大海在最初離開
had stopped to question why the ocean had left in the first place.
Prior先生？
Mr. Prior?
我是惠靈頓警局的Farno探員
I am Detective Inspector Farnon from Wellington CIV.
這是Dunleavy探員
This is Detective Dunleavy.
我有搜查令
I've a warrant to search these premises.
需要你去警局回答一些問題
And I'll need you to accompany me to the station for questioning.
我需要你的護照和車鑰匙
I'll need your passport and keys to your car.
我知道Celia常去一個密室和你見面
I believe there's a shed where Celia used to visit you.
好，我們送你回去
Right then, let's get you home.
上週日Celia為什麼去你家？
Why did Celia come to your place last Sunday?
你聽見我的問題了嗎？
Did you hear the question?
聽見了
Yes.
我知道她定期來見你
I understand she visited you regularly.
她來得目的是什麼？
What was the nature of the visits?
我們談一些事
We talked about things.
什麼事？
What things?
歐洲
Europe.
書
Books.
Celia想成為作家
Celia wants to be a writer.
我不是肉，我不是血
I am not flesh. I am not blood.
他們可以盡其所能，但是他們看不見我
They can look all they like but they'll never see me.
如果這一生我無法再聽見你的愛，握你的手
If I never hear your love or hold your hand again in this life,
向我保證死後我們會再見
promise me we will touch when I am dead.
詩的名字是'Poem for a Lonely Friend'
It's called 'Poem for a Lonely Friend'.
你覺得自己孤獨嗎, Paul？
Would you consider yourself lonely, Paul?
謝謝
Thank you.
請關上門
Would you keep that door closed, please.
為什麼Celia堅持來看你，不顧她父母的反對？
Why did Celia keep visiting you even though her parents had forbidden it?
父母？
Parents?
母親
Mother.
我想她從我身上看到了一些東西
I guess she saw something in me.
什麼東西？
And what was that?
我不是Celia.
Well, I'm not Celia.
那也許你可以告訴我們，你從她身上看到了什麼
Then perhaps you'd like to tell me what it was you saw in her?
我知道這很困難
I know this is diffi--
我記得成為她的感覺
I remember being her.
這次你又做了什麼？
What did you do this time?
讓我一個人呆著
Come on, leave me alone now .
走開
Go away.
走吧你，走吧，讓我一個人呆著
Just fucking go, come on, leave me alone.
我不需要你, Celia，走開
I don't need this shit, Celia.Just go.
怎麼了
What?
我媽跟你說了什麼了嗎？
Did mom say something to you?
你媽威脅說要告訴學校
Your mum threatened to ring the school, yeah.
可以了嗎？
Okay?
不，不可以
No, it's not ok.
她太他媽不講理了
God, she's so fucking presumptuous.
誰他媽在乎她怎麼想的
Who the fuck cares what she thinks?
她那個討厭的男友穿著像船那麼大的鞋子
She's got a fucking boyfriend he wears boat shoes.
他也給她買了一雙，現在他們一個鼻子出氣了
He brought her a pair now they're both wearing them.
在這兒他媽一隻船都看不到
You never see a fucking boat around here.
我來是要告訴你我參加那個比賽了
I just came to tell you that I entered the contest .
那很好，加油吧
Well that's great, now get going.
我們不是不可以做朋友, Paul.
It's not illegal that we're friends or something, Paul.
是你說的，我們不該在意別人的想法
It was you who said that we shouldn't care what other people think of us.
難道你只是說說而已
Or were you just saying that?
你和我媽曾是戀人，現在我們是朋友
You know how you and mom used to go out and now it me and you that are friends.
我感覺我這一生都有你這個朋友
I feel like I've known you my whole life.
是啊，這個世界很小
Yeah well, it's a small world.
世界並不小
It isn't a small world.
你們當時相愛嗎？
Were you guys in love?
你們把對方的名字紋在腳趾上，一定不只是兒戲
There must've been something going on if you tattooed each others feet.
有些難以想像你在她身上看到了什麼
It's a little hard to imagine what you saw in her.
你不是唯一一個對父母抱有這樣想法的人
Well, you're not the first person to feel that way about their parents.
算了，都是很久以前的事了
Anyway, it's a long time ago.
也許就是那樣
I know it wasn't planned.
媽那時才16歲
Mom was only 16.
如果你心裡有什麼事，會告訴我的吧
You'd tell me if you knew anything, eh?
保證嗎？
Is that a promise?
行了
Oh stuff it.
淋雨去吧，走
Let's get wet. Come on.
Mazzy Star "Take Everything"
天啊
Oh, geez!
Andrew, Jonathan？
Andrew, Jonathan?
我們從教堂回家，想進來坐坐
We were on our way home from church and thought we'd stop in for a cuppa.
該死
Fuck.
太冷了
It's freezing!
你看到他們在造的新東西嗎？
Have you see this new thing that they're building?
像一個大糧倉
It looks like a giant barn.
我去一下洗手間
I'm gonna go to the bathroom.
我去燒水
I'll put the kettle on.
Celia Steimer的家人和朋友
Family and friends of Celia Steimer
正協助警方尋找她
are doing everything possible to help police find her.
超過50名志願者從水路尋找失蹤女孩
More than 50 volunteers are now scouring waterways and bushlands
在馬歇爾路森林
in the Marshall road forest.
這位16歲的中學生
The 16-year-old Rapari Junction HS student
失蹤超過一周
has been missing now for more than a week.
Robin Farland探員表示
Detective Robin Farland says
他們不得不考慮種種可能性
they have to consider every option.
她還表示一位當地市民正在幫助他們的調查
She acknowledged a local man is helping them with their inquiries
警方將會拜訪當地的每一家人
and the police will be visiting every house in the area.
他不會有事的
He'll be fine.
讓他們處理吧
Let them handle it.
請用煙灰缸
Please just use an ashtray.
好的
Okay.
聽著，我跟Alexandria的律師談過了
Listen, I spoke to the lawyer in Alexandria
他過去處理過這樣的事
and he reckons he's handled this sort of thing before.
他想讓你明天一早給他打個電話
He wants you to give him a call first thing in the morning.
嘿，你說怎樣的性交姿勢能生出最醜的孩子
Hey, what sexual position creates the ugliest offspring?
怎樣的性交姿勢能生出...
What sexual position creates--
我不知道, Paul
I don't know, Paul.
問問你媽
Ask your mother.
你能想像如果她現在看到我們會怎樣嗎？
Can you imagine if she saw us now?
你能想像嗎，你覺得她會說什麼？
Can you imagine that? What do you think she'd say?
兄弟倆邊喝邊談
Two brothers having a drink and a chat.
你說呢？她會驕傲嗎？
What do you think? She'd be proud, or what?
你在說什麼？
Why are you doing this?
什麼什麼？
Doing what?
你知道什麼
You know exactly what.
你為什麼就不能跟我說
Why can't you just talk to me?
去你的
Fuck you.
你他媽在看什麼？沒見過兄弟倆說話？
What the fuck are you looking at? Never seen two brothers talking before?
你想談，那我們談
You want to talk, let's talk.
別忘了你醉醺醺闖到這裡
Forget the fact you come in here blind drunk
打斷我的會議，忽然就提起媽來了
and interrupt a meeting but then you just bring up mom like that?
我說你怎麼敢？我知道你現在不太好, Paul,
I mean how dare you? I realize you are in a spot of bother, Paul,
不過那並不代表你可以這樣做
but that doesn't give you the right to behave like this.
想知道真相？你從來就沒有關心過母親
The truth? You were never there for mom.
她病的時候，你在哪裡
When she was sick, where the hell were you?
太好了，現在你有意見了，好啊，Andrew
Brilliant. So you do have an opinion. OK Andrew.
你他媽什麼意思？我都不能接近她
What the fuck is that supposed to mean? I couldn't get near her.
都怪我好了，我還得扮演你的角色，忘了嗎？
Blame it all on me. I had to be you. Did you know that?
你他媽想想清楚
You made fucking sure of it.
快樂的三人世界：Andy，媽媽，還有上帝
The happy little fucking threesome: Andy, mom and God.
沒有別人打擾
No one else invited.
你拋棄了她
You abandoned her.
你拋棄了她, Paul. 你從來沒有邁出一步...
You abandoned her, Paul. And you never took one single step towards--
你沒忘了爸吧
他做錯過事，可是他接受了我
at least for all his faults, he let me in. He let me in.
你連他的葬禮都沒有趕到 現卻在站在這裡為他說話
You were late for his funeral, remember? And you're gonna stand here defending for him.
聽我說，Paul，你聽我說
Listen to me Paul, you listen, listen to me.
有時候我看著你
You know sometimes I look at you
看到的都是他
and all I see is him.
只是他
Just him.
那令我沮喪
I find that quite disheartening.
至少我沒他媽娶我的媽
Yeah well, at least I didn't marry my fucking mother.
她一直是那樣的，還是只有見到你時那樣？
Has she always been like that or just when she met you?
去死吧，Paul
Go to hell, Paul.
警察表示血跡屬於失蹤的女孩
Police confirm blood traces belong to missing girl.
打開
Just open it!
Celia, 把信封給我
Celia, give me the fucking letter carta.
沒用的
It doesn't matter.
打開，打開好嗎？
Open it. Will you just open it?
不，別打開
No! Don't open it.
打開
Open it!
我不想
I don't want to.
不想？
No?
不想
No.
誰得了第一呢？
Wonder who came in first?
在兩千多名參賽者中
Amid the 2000 or so entries
我們很欣賞Steimers小姐的文章
we were delighted with Ms Steimers' story.
這篇作品顯示了一個年輕人的才華
This work shows an emerging remarkable talent for someone so young.
它捕獲了一種美感，神秘感，和迷失感
It catches a sense of beauty, mystery and loss
同時並未喪失清醒
without ever losing sight of what might be.
誰第一...
You wonder who came first?
我來告訴你
I'll tell you who came first.
很可能是年長你三倍的某個人 值得拿第一的某個人
Someone three times your age, probably, someone who bloody well deserved to come first.
謝謝你讓我感覺如此特別
Thank you for making it special for me.
小屋，還有其他一切
The den and everything.
我要抽根煙，來享受這美景
I need a cigarette to cope with this sort of scenery.
我去車裡拿煙，馬上回來
In the car.I'll be back in a tic.
能把外套給我嗎？
Can you leave me your jacket?
你今晚出門嗎，我想要你看著Sam
Are you gonna be home tonight? I need you to baby sit Sam.
Celia, 我在跟你說話
Celia, I asked you a question.
該死
Fuck!
他是我爸爸嗎？
Is he my father?
如果是那樣簡單就好了
I wish it were that simple.
嘿
Hey, you!
怎麼了
What's up?
你知道嗎？
Did you know?
回答我，你知道嗎？
Answer me! Did you know?
哦, Celia...
Oh, Celia...
我知道你拍下那個女孩的照片之後做了什麼
I know what you did when you took the photo of that girl.
你走開了，你離開了她
You walked away and left her.
那就是你退出提名的原因，這樣你不用再為此困擾了
That's why you withdrew the entry so you wouldn't even have to deal with her.
你不知道...
You don't know--
別說了
don't!
她只是另一張照片嗎？
Was she just another photo?
只是你為了解開該死的戰爭迷題 拍下的一張照片嗎？
Just another picture of this fucking war puzzle that you try to figure out?
她是另一個我嗎？
Was she just like me?
她只是你隨便扔掉和忘記的人嗎？
Was she just someone you could pick up and throw away and forget about?
你怎麼可以這樣
How do you live with yourself?
Andrew! Penny!
你們在嗎？
Are you there?
開開門
Will you just open the door?
我只是想要個落腳之處
I just need somewhere to stay.
Penny, 我知道你在裡面
Come on Penny, I know you're in there.
Jonathan, 報紙上寫的那些
You know Jonathan, all that stuff in the papers,
只是猜測
that's all just speculation.
都是垃圾
All right? It's rubbish.
他們沒有證據
They have no proof.
我還是你的叔叔
I'm still your uncle.
不，你不是
No you're not.
我們都覺得你他媽太笨了
We both think you're fucking stupid.
你說什麼？
What did you say?
放開我
Leave me alone!
我希望他們殺了你
I hope they kill you.
我希望他們...
I hope they--
沒事的
It's okay!
沒事的，我知道你喜歡她
It's alright. I know you like her.
聽著，你得告訴我「你們」是什麼意思
Listen, you have to tell me what you meant by "both of you".
看著我
Look at me.
「我們都覺得你很笨」是什麼意思？
What did you mean by "both of us think you're stupid"?
告訴我「我們」是誰
Tell me what you meant by "both of us".
我不會傷害你，我保證不會傷害你
I'm not gonna hurt you. I promise I won't hurt you.
什麼意思, Jonathan？
What is it, Jonathan?
我在找我的相機
I was looking for my camera.
我以為他藏起來是為了保護你
I thought he was hiding it to protect you.
他在哪兒
Where is he?
明天以前都在教堂
In Christchurch till tomorrow.
Paul!
Paul, 你在嗎？
Paul, are you there?
河邊
RIVER
我剛聽律師說
I just heard from the lawyer.
你不想賣是什麼意思？
What do you mean you don't want to sell?
你不行，我手頭正緊...
You can't. I'm up to my eyeballs--
你他媽在幹嘛
What the hell did you do that for?
起來
Get up!
你想做什麼？把它藏到我家，跟那張地圖一樣？
What were you going to do? Plant it at my place like the atlas?
你不需要這樣的
This is really unnecessary
好吧，好吧
Okay! Okay!
我曾經想過你為什麼就那樣走了
There was a time I wondered why you up and left.
你知道他要做什麼的，不是嗎？
You knew what he was up to, didn't you?
至少看著我說
At least look at me and tell me
在你扣動扳機之前
before you pull the trigger.
你知道最可悲的是什麼嗎？
You know the really sad part?
直到看了遺囑，我才知道
I didn't even find out until I read the will.
我是那樣無知
That's how far back I was.
那時我怎麼會懂, Paul
But then how was I to know, Paul?
我還是個孩子，十五歲的孩子
I was only a kid, a 15-year-old kid.
你走得一乾二淨，把我留給了那個卑賤的人
You killed me when you walked away and left me with that evil piece of scum.
你以為你他媽會有第二次機會？
You think you even get a second fucking chance?
你知道的，畜牲
You knew, you bastard!
你還有膽回來，把那野種帶到我們家
And you had the gall to come back here and bring that thing into our house.
我媽媽的家！
My mother's house!
天知道你和她幹了些什麼，有其父必有其子
And god knows what you're doing with her, but then like father like son.
Andrew, 你他媽不知道你在說什麼
Andrew, you don't know what the fuck you're talking about.
他幹了你那年輕的婊子
He was screwing that teenage whore of yours.
不!
No!
- 他干了，你知道的 - 不!
- He was. You knew it. - No!
你走開了
And you walked.
Andrew，別說了，這他媽與你無關
Andrew no! It's got nothing to fucking do with you!
你親眼看見了
You saw it with your own eyes!
01:48:11,917